zippcast.com 2015-12-30

# ZippCast | Privacy Policy

**Updated as of June 7, 2011**

The following describes privacy practices specific to ZippCast. 

**Browsing ZippCast** You can view media on ZippCast without having a ZippCast Account. You also can contact us through the ZippCast Help Center or by emailing us directly without having to register for an account. 

**Your ZippCast Account.** For some activities on ZippCast, like uploading media, posting comments, flagging media, or watching restricted media, you need a ZippCast Account. We ask for some personal information when you create an account, including your email address and a password, which is used to protect your account from unauthorized access. 

**Usage Information.** When you use ZippCast, we may record information about your usage of the site, such as the channels, groups and favorites you subscribe to, which other users you communicate with, the media you view, the frequency and size of data transfers, and information you display about yourself as well as information you click on in ZippCast (including UI elements, settings). If you are logged in, we may associate that information with your ZippCast Account. In order to ensure the quality of our service to you, we may place a tag (also called a "web beacon") in HTML-based customer support emails or other communications with you in order to confirm delivery. 

**Content Uploaded to Site.** Any personal information or video content that you voluntarily disclose online (e.g., video comments, your profile page) may be collected and used by others. If you download the ZippCast Uploader, your copy includes a unique application number. This number, and information about your installation of the Uploader (version number, language) will be sent to ZippCast when the Uploader automatically checks for updates and will be used to update your version of the Uploader. 

If you submit personal information to ZippCast, we may use that information to operate, maintain, and improve the features and functionality of ZippCast, and to process any flagging activity or other communication you send to us. 

We do not use your email address or other personal information to send commercial or marketing messages without your consent. We may use your email address without further consent for non-marketing or administrative purposes (such as notifying you of major ZippCast changes or for customer service purposes). You also can choose how often ZippCast sends you email updates in your ZippCast Account settings page. 

We use cookies, web beacons, and log file information to: (a) store information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit ZippCast; (b) provide custom, personalized content and information; (c) monitor the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns; (d) monitor aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors and pages viewed; and (e) track your entries, submissions, and status in promotions, sweepstakes, and contests. 

When you create a ZippCast Account, some information about your ZippCast Account and your account activity will be provided to other users of ZippCast. This may include the date you opened your ZippCast Account, the date you last logged into your ZippCast Account, your age (if you choose to make it public), the country and the number of media files you have watched. 

Your ZippCast Account name, not your email address, is displayed to other users when you engage in certain activities on ZippCast, such as when you upload media or send messages through ZippCast. Other users can contact you by leaving a message or comment on the site. 

Any media that you submit to ZippCast may be redistributed through the internet and other media channels, and may be viewed by other ZippCast users or the general public. 

You may also choose to add personal information which may include your name, gender, profile picture or other details, that will be visible to other users on your ZippCast Account channel page. If you choose to add certain features to your ZippCast Account channel page, then these features and your activity associated with these features will be displayed to other users and may be aggregated and shared with your friends or other users. Such shared activity may include your favorite media, media you rated and media that you have uploaded. 

If you have a ZippCast Account, you may update or correct your personal profile information, email preferences and privacy settings at any time by visiting your [account profile page](http://www.zippcast.com/my_profile_info). 

You may control the information that is available to other users and your confirmed friends at any time by editing your ZippCast Account and the features that are included on your channel page. If you have enabled Active Sharing, other users may see that you, as identified by your account name, not your email address, are watching the same video. 

You may, of course, decline to submit personal information through ZippCast, in which case you can still view media and explore ZippCast, but ZippCast may not be able to provide certain services to you. Some advanced ZippCast features may use other Google services like AdSense. The privacy notices of those services govern the use of your personal information associated with them. 

ZippCast strives to provide you with relevant and useful advertising and we use the [DoubleClick cookie](http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/dart_adserving.aspx), as well as other third party ad serving systems, to do so. We may use a range of information including cookies, web beacons, IP addresses, usage data and other non-personal information about your computer or device (such as browser type and operating system) to provide you with relevant advertising. While you are logged in or logged out of your ZippCast Account, we may also show you advertising based on non-personally identifiable information you have provided to us in your ZippCast Account.

We use the [DoubleClick cookie](http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/dart_adserving.aspx) on ZippCast to help advertisers and publishers serve and manage ads on this site and other Google and AdSense partner websites. Advertisers may serve ads based on interests and demographic categories associated with non-personally identifiable online activity, such as media viewed, frequency of uploading or activity on other AdSense partner sites. Advertisers may also serve ads to you based on previous activity on that advertiser's website or based on non-personally identifiable information from other companies. This non-personally identifiable information is held separately from your ZippCast Account data, or other personally identifying information in our possession.

You may view, edit and add to the categories used to provide you with interest-based advertising in the [Ads Preferences Manager](http://www.google.com/ads/preferences?hl=en-US) for the DoubleClick cookie. Your ads preferences will be respected across ZippCast, AdSense partner sites and Google sites using the DoubleClick cookie to serve such ads. To learn about the privacy policies of third parties that advertisers may use to display ads on ZippCast, and to opt out, you can check out the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp) opt-out page. 

You also may choose to [opt out of the DoubleClick cookie](http://optout.doubleclick.com/cgi-bin/optoutgoogle.pl) at any time. If you select the DoubleClick opt-out cookie, ads delivered to your browser by our ad-serving technology will not be served based on the DoubleClick cookie.

Other third-party ad serving companies may display ads on ZippCast, provided they comply with our ad serving requirements. ZippCast does not provide any personal information to these third-party ad servers or ad networks without your consent. You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers or ad networks for more information on their practices and for instructions on how to opt-out of certain practices. ZippCast's privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites. Any data obtained by third-party ad servers subsequently shared with ZippCast is maintained and dealt with by ZippCast in accordance with this privacy policy.

For questions concerning the product or your account, please check out the [Help](http://www.zippcast.com/t/help.php) page. 

ZippCast Privacy

1308 Linwood Ave.  
Niagara Falls, NY 14305  
USA
